<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Front-End Web on Sorush Khajepor - Numerical programming and app development</title>
    <link>https://iamsorush.com/tags/front-end-web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Front-End Web on Sorush Khajepor - Numerical programming and app development</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 19:20:06 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamsorush.com/tags/front-end-web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create a table of content from headings of a Hugo post</title>
      <link>https://iamsorush.com/posts/table-of-content-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 19:20:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsorush.com/posts/table-of-content-blog/</guid>
      <description>Goal I want to write code to get a table of content (ToC) for each blog post automatically. It is created and shown on the right-hand side of the content of a post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a video to a Hugo post</title>
      <link>https://iamsorush.com/posts/add-video-to-hugo-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 18:30:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsorush.com/posts/add-video-to-hugo-post/</guid>
      <description>I want to add a video to a Hugo blog post. The video is hosted on my website, so it is not a Youtube or Vimeo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to have math equations in your website</title>
      <link>https://iamsorush.com/posts/math-equations-in-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 23:33:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsorush.com/posts/math-equations-in-website/</guid>
      <description>If you want to write math equations in your website or blog, plain text becomes immediately illegible when writing something more complex than addition and subtraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a lightweight weblog homepage with Bootstrap and Html</title>
      <link>https://iamsorush.com/posts/create-lightweight-weblog-homepage-with-bootstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 20:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsorush.com/posts/create-lightweight-weblog-homepage-with-bootstrap/</guid>
      <description>I want to create a lightweight homepage of a weblog with HTML, Bootstrap and a bit of custom CSS. No javascript, no database, no WordPress is used. It should be a lightweight and fast static website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a simple component, using Blazor, HTML, and CSS: Word Block</title>
      <link>https://iamsorush.com/posts/how-to-create-a-simple-component-using-blazor-html-and-css-word-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 22:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsorush.com/posts/how-to-create-a-simple-component-using-blazor-html-and-css-word-block/</guid>
      <description>Using .Net Blazor, I want to create a simple word-block which is a rectangle that contains a word with an X button at its right side. Clicking on X the word-block disappears.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
